[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So principal component analysis is based on linear algebra,
主成分分析基于线性代数，
on eigenvectors and eigenvalues of matrices.
矩阵的特征向量和特征值。
You don't necessarily have to understand those details in order to use
对于使用主成分分析来说，
Principle component analysis.
并不须要理解那些细节。
If you have a package that will perform principle component analysis then it will
如果你有一个能够做主成分分析的软件包
just convert the data from a high dimensional form into a low dimensional
它将会把数据从高维形式转换为低维形式
form that you can display.
以便于显示
So as we lay out data, and look at ways of laying out data based on relationships.
所以 我们要展示数据 并寻求基于数据间关系的来展示数据
It's useful to look at some other techniques for laying out data.
看看其它数据展示技术也是很有用处的
Even if the data does have variables, or
即使数据包含变量
attributes, or coordinates associated with it.
特性或者坐标
So, one of these techniques is called principal component analysis.
这些技术中的一个被称为主成分分析
If I have a data set, like this one,
如果我有一个数据集合 好比这一个
each data value has an x coordinate and a y coordinate.
每一个数据值有一个 x 坐标 和一个 y 坐标
But you can really see the main variance of the data is happening along
但是 你能看到数据的主要变化发生在
this diagonal direction, and
沿着对角线方向
the data isn't varying much perpendicularly to that direction.
而且 在与对角线垂直的方向 数据并没有很大的变化
So the x coordinate doesn't entirely capture the data, and
因此 x坐标不能完全刻画数据 并且
the y coordinate doesn't entirely capture the variance of the data.
y坐标也不能完全刻画数据的变化
the variance is actually happening in a different direction.
实际上 数据的变化是在一个不同的方向
So we can look at the variance of the data as being
因此，我们可将数据的变化
the actual dimension where things are changing along the data.
看成是事物随数据变化的实际维度
And it may not be exactly the x direction or the y direction.
这个维度不一定正好在x方向或者y方向
It may be a combination of them.
它或许是x和y方向的一个组合
And as we look at higher dimensional data,
此外 当我们分析更高维的数据时
we may find that the data is varying in some direction, that's a combination of X,
我们也许会发现 数据变化的方向
Y, Z, W...however many dimensions you have.
是X, Y, W ... 或更多维度的组合
Principle component analysis helps us find these directions where the data is varying
主成分分析帮助我们找到那些方向 在那里
a lot.
其实它未被大规模宣传数据变化很大
And also the directions that the data is varying a little bit.
以及数据变化很小的方向
And then we can reorient it so
然后 我们可以对数据重新定向
that we can just display the dimensions where the data's varying a lot and
以便我们能够只显示 数据变化很大的那些维度
ignore the directions that the data is varying a little bit.
而忽略数据变化很小的那些方向
And then align those dimension with the displayed dimensions.
然后 将那些维度对齐至显示维度。
So in order to perform principle component analysis, we have to analyze the data.
因此 为了进行主成分分析 我们必须分析数据
First we have to take the data and then we have to subtract the mean.
首先 我们要拿到数据 然后减去数据的均值
So for each of these data items we're going to add them up, divide by the total
于是 对每一个数据项 我们要把所有数据加起来
and that'll give us the, by the total number and then that'll give us the mean.
再除以数据项的总数 这样就计算出数据的均值
We subtract that from all the data.
我们把均值从所有数据中减掉
That centers the data about the origin,
这样把数据的中心放到了原点
and then we're going to compute this covariance matrix.
然后，我们要来计算协方差矩阵。
So it's a big matrix, if our data elements are four dimensions,
如果数据元素是四维的 那将是一个很大的矩阵
X, Y, Z and W then the covariance matrix would be a four by four matrix.
X Y Z和W 那么 协方差矩阵应该是一个4乘4的矩阵
It'll have this many dimensions by this many dimensions.
它将会有这么多维度乘以这么多维度
And it's just the data items, after you've subtracted their mean,
这只是数据项 在减去它们到均值之后
multiplied by the other coordinates of the data items and then averaged.
乘以数据项的其它坐标 再取平均
And that covariance matrix will yield a symmetric matrix because, for
那个协方差矩阵会是一个对称矩阵 这是因为
example, yi times xi is going to be equal to xi time yi.
举例来说 yi 乘以xi 等于xi 乘以yi
And so you can think of a matrix, a large matrix, as
所以你可以把矩阵 一个大的矩阵想象成
something that transforms a sphere in high dimensions into some kind of ellipsoid.
把一个高维球面 转换成某一种椭球
It's going to stretch it out in a certain direction.
它将会在某个特定方向拉伸出去
And when you square that matrix, multiply it times its transpose,
对那个矩阵进行平方 再乘以其转置
it's going to create a square symmetric matrix similar to that covariance matrix.
这会产生一个类似于 协方差矩阵的对称方阵
When we pull out the Eigenvectors and the Eigenvalues of that matrix,
当我们取出这个矩阵的 特征向量和特征值时
these are directions that, when you multiply the matrix times that direction,
它们是这样的一些方向 当用矩阵乘以这些方向时
it's the same thing as just multiplying it by a scalar value.
其结果等于用矩阵乘以一个标量值
So these are directions where if a matrix is stretching a sphere
如果一个矩阵将球面拉伸成椭球
into an ellipsoid, so the directions of the principle axis of that ellipsoid.
这些方向就是那个椭球的主轴
And so if you have a lot of variance, you'll pull out an eigenvector in this
如果数据有很大的差异 你会得到这样一个特征向量
direction that's stretching the sphere out into a long ellipsoid.
沿这个方向 球面被拉伸成一个很长的椭球
There may be two principal directions in which case,
也有可能有两个主方向， 在这种情况下，
that sphere gets stretched out into this cookie shape.
球面被拉伸成这样的饼干形状
Principal component analysis finds those eigenvectors, the direction where
主成分分析就是寻找 那些特征向量
the data is varying the most and then, it ignores
既数据变化最大的方向 然后它忽略
the small eigenvectors, the directions where the data is varying the least and
小的特征向量 既那些数据变化最小的方向
that way we can display the two or three most varying
这样 我们就可以只显示 两个或者三个数据变化最大的方向
directions of data without displaying all of the dimensions of the data.
而不用显示数据的所有维度
So here's an example.
让我们来看一个例子
I worked with a group of people a few years ago.
几年前 我和一个小组的人一起工作
On a method for computing the geometry
致力于计算一个在受损下颌骨中
of a scaffolding to support bone growth in damaged mandibles.
支撑骨骼生长的支架的几何形状
And so we needed some geometry for
所以 我们需要一些下颌骨的几何信息
a mandible in order to figure out healthy mandible, and a damaged
以便弄清楚健康的下颌骨 以及一个受损的下颌骨
mandible to be able to do a subtraction operation to find this damaged piece.
就能将两者相减 从而找到受损的部分
So if we don't have an undamaged mandible, how could we find a mandible that
因此 如果我们没有一个未受损的下颌骨 怎么能找到这样一个下颌骨
was the shape of the damaged mandible before the damage happened?
它是受损的下颌骨 在损伤发生之前的形状呢?
And the way we did this was we scanned in a bunch of these mandibles and
我们采取的方法是 我们扫描了一批这样的下颌骨
we specifically measured the shape of these five data points.
并特别测量了形体上这五个数据点
And so we had this big database of 40 some mandibles, and
我们有一个大的数据库 有40多个下颌骨的数据
each data point, each of those 40 data points,
其每一个数据点 即那40个数据点中的每一个
was 15-dimensional because each of these three data points was three-dimensional.
都是15维的 因为这五（更正 不是三）个数据点 中的每一个都是三维的
So five three dimensional data points gave me 15 dimensions.
因此 五个三维数据点是15维
So I could describe the shape of a mandible as a 15 dimensional point.
于是 我可以将一个下颌骨的形状 描述为一个15维的点
We then perform principal component analysis to find three main variations.
然后 我们进行了主成分分析 来找出三个主要的变化方向
Three of the directions in this 15 dimensional space
即在15维空间中
where these mandibles were changing the most.
这些颌骨在那三个方向变化最大
And they were kind of this direction here that pulls the jaw down,
它们大概是这个将颌骨下拖的方向
this direction that causes the jaw to kind of extrude in the front, and
这个使颌骨向前突出的方向
then a direction that caused the jaw to move to the side.
以及这个使颌骨侧移的方向
And so based on that, we can plot all of our data points and
于是 基于这个分析结果 我们可以画出所有的数据点
this is an example of the mandible, all the different data sets of our mandibles.
这是一个下颌骨的例子 我们有的下颌骨的不同数据集合
Plotted as a single, just overlaid on top of each other.
先画成单个的颌骨 再将它们互相重叠起来
Each one of these corresponds to a position in this space of mandibles.
它们中的每一个 对应这个下颌骨空间中一个位置
And the three dimensions here that I'm visualizing these mandibles in
这些三维的下颌骨可视化图形
corresponds to a direction, a variation
代表着一个维度及其变化
that I found from that principal component analysis, each of those three dimensions.
即是利用主成分分析对每一个 三维维度的分析得到的
So each of these points corresponds to a point in a 15 dimensional space, but
这里的每一个点 对应于15维空间中的一点
I'm plotting them in a 3 dimensional space according to
根据它们变化最大的方向
the direction of their highest variance,
我将它们在一个3维空间中展现出来
as represented by the eigenvector of that covariance matrix.
方向的变化度则是用协方差矩阵 的特征向量来表示
And so that performs a form of dimensionality reduction,
这样 我们进行了一种形式的降维
where we can take high dimensional data and plotted in a low-dimensional space for
这样 我们可以将高维的数据 在一个低维空间中进行可视化
visualization by basically focusing on the dimensions where we're seeing variation
总的来说 是集中注意力在 在那些数据有变化的维度
and ignoring the directions where we're not seeing variation in the data.
而忽略那些没有变化的维度
So in order to implement multidimensional scaling, you need to do an optimization.
所以为了实现多维缩放 需要进行优化
You don't necessarily have to code up your own optimization to do that.
你不到不一定需要自己来编写优化方法
For example when I computed the multidimensional scaling of the cities
例如 在我的例子中计算城市的多维缩放时
in my example, they were computed in Excel using an optimization package I enabled.
它们是在Excel中计算的 启用了其中的一个优化功能块
So you don't have to write an optimization algorithm from scratch.
所以 你不需要从头开始写一个优化算法
You can just use an existing optimization program.
你完全可以使用一个现有的优化程序
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community